Finding Aid for Satakunta Region immigrant letters, 1880-1964
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Satakunta Region immigrant letters
1880-1964
Turun Yliopisto. Yleisen Historian Laitos.
89340 Bd microcopy
The Institute of General History at the University of Turku, Finland (Turun Yliopisto. Yleisen Historian Laitos) microfilmed thousands of letters from Satakunta region in 1964. The letters were written by Finnish emigrants to their families and friends in Finland.
25 microfilms positive
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The letters were collected under the auspices of the Institute of General History, University of Turku 5574
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
The Institute of General History at the University of Turku collated this collection of letters of immigrants to the United States and Canada sent to family and friends in Satakunta Province, Finland, between March 1, 1964 and October 15, 1964. To begin this undertaking, the Radio of Finland had several programs where they made this project known. Also there were several articles in Satakunta newspapers. Until the middle of April only youth societies collected letters. Later the high schools and a couple of Lions Clubs in Satakunta participated as well: In addition, the Students Union of Satakunta took part. Financial help came from Suomi-Seura (Finland Society) and the Historical Society of Finland.
There are about 6000 letters in this collection. Most of the letters have been written by emigrants who used to live in Satakunta but there are also some from persons who lived in other provinces before emigrating. There are also post cards, diaries and passports in the collection. The letters were written to residents of Satakunta from 1880 to 1964. Although most of the letters were sent from the United States and Canada, there were a few letters from South America, Australia, New Zealand and Soviet Union.
The collection was arranged by towns (also known as parishes or municipalities). Within each town series the letters of each recipient were kept together. The owners of the letters are in chronological order according to the emigrating year of their correspondents.
Every collector of letters filled out a questionnaire for each writer. The questionnaire is at the beginning of the sender's letters. In the upper right corner of the questionnaire there is a code that includes the abbreviation of the town and the location of the sender.
Questionnaire used in collecting America letters:
The owner of the letters (name and address)
The writer of the letters (name and last address)
The relationship between the owner and the writer
When left for America
Who were they visiting in America
Why left
Home town in Finland
The occupation of the parents
How large was the family of the parents of the emigrant
Was the emigrant married when he left Finland
Did the wife and children emigrate, too
Did the emigrant get married in America
What year
The nationality of the spouse
The occupation of the emigrant when emigrated
Had the emigrant ever been working outside the home town before emigrating
How did the emigrant go to America (route and vehicle)
The first workplace in America
What kind of work
Where did the emigrant live the longest time in America
What kind of work
Other members of the group who emigrated at the same time: name, hometown, return to Finland
The later life of the emigrant: did/did not return to Finland
If applicable, why did the emigrant return
Return route and vehicle
Occupation after return
The number of the letters (photos, diaries etc.) in the enclosed questionnaire envelope
The owner donates the letters/loans them only for microfilming
The collector of the letters (name and address)
To be filled by the Institute of General History
Documents in this collection contain the following abbreviations for the names of the town or parish from an immigrant came:
AHL = Ahlainen
ALAS = Alastaro
EURA = Eura
E-KI = Eurajoki
HIN = Hinnerjoki
H-KI = Honkajoki
H-TI = Honkilahti
HUIT = Huittinen
HAM = Hämeenkyrö
IKA = Ikaalinen
JAM = Jämijärvi
KAN = Kankaanpää
K-KU = Karkku
KAR = Karvia
KIH = Kihniö
KIIK = Kiikka
KNEN = Kiikoinen
KOK = Kokemaki
KUL = Kullaa
KOY=Köyliö
LAP = Lappi Tl.
LAV = Lavia
LOIM = Loimaa
MEL = Mellilä
MER = Merikarvia
MET = Metsämaa
MOU = Mouhijarvi
NOOR = Noormarkku
PAR = Parkano
POM = Pomarkku
PORI = City of Pori and rural parish of Pori
PUN = Punkalaidun
RAUM = Rauma: city and rural parish
SIIK = Siikainen
SUOD = Suodenniemi
SAK = Säkylä
TYRV = Tyrvää and Vammala
VAMP = Vampula
Subjects:
Finnish Americans--Michigan.; Finnish Americans.; United States--Emigration and immigration.; Finland--Emigration and immigration.; Immigrants--United States.
- Ahlainen, letters to
  - Bertta Westerlund
    - from: Hilma Virtanen, Cal., 1958; 9 items (Reel 1)
    - from: E. Abrahamsson
      - Ill., 1958; 2 items (Reel 1)
      - Ironwood, Mich., 1958-1959; 4 items (Reel 1)
      - Ill., 1960-1962; 3 items (Reel 1)
      - Ironwood, Mich., 1963-1964; 6 items (Reel 1)
- Alastaro, letters to
  - Sanni Anttila
    - from: Mary Ström. Sask., 1946-1955; 5 items (Reel 1)
  - Frans Junnila
    - from: Kalle Junnila. Wis., 1950-1954; 4 items (Reel 1)
  - Maria Salmi
    - from: Hilja Wuori. Fla., 1963; 1 items (Reel 1)
  - Aarne Hinkkanen
    - from: Reino Allen. Quebec, 1957; 1 items (Reel 1)
  - Erkki Kuisma
    - from: Saima Hiltunen. Detroit, Mich., 1956-1959; 3 items (Reel 1)
- Eura, letters to
  - Lisa Kivimaki
    - from: Frans Nyman. Soviet Union, Minnesota, 1880-1892; 21 items (Reel 1)
  - Maunu Kunnas
    - from: Emil Aalto. Kaleva, Mich., 1902; 1 items (Reel 1)
  - Torsti Laitinen
    - from: Selma Lindgren. Calif., 1946-1961; 14 items (Reel 1)
  - Lyyli Lilius
    - from: Sandra Alander. Oregon, 1947-1957; 5 items (Reel 1)
  - Hilma Linden
    - from: Nestor Kunnas. Alta., 1925-1951; 2 items (Reel 1)
  - Vilho Mäkinen
    - from: Frank Maki. Ohio, Wyo. Minn., 1930-1956; 6 items (Reel 1)
  - Manda Kallio
    - from: Edward Tergs. Ill., 1950-1961; 2 items (Reel 1)
  - Maunu Heino
    - from: Väinö Heino. Mass., Minn., 1961-1964; 4 items (Reel 1)
  - Nestor Mäkilä
    - from: Aina Jokinen. Minn., N.Y., 1919-1963; 13 items (Reel 1)
  - Tilda Karhu
    - from: Maria Aalto. Mass., 1945; 2 items (Reel 1)
  - Lyydia Lehtomäki
    - from: Frank Ranta. Wash., 1955-1959; 2 items (Reel 1)
  - Ester Rinne
    - from: Ida Raski. Ohio, 1954-1963; 14 items (Reel 1)
  - Lahja Kivimaa
    - from: Evert Marjanen. Minn., 1962; 5 items (Reel 1)
  - Asser Äärilä
    - from: Hilma Isotalo. Wash., 1949-1959; 7 items (Reel 1)
  - Hilja Koivisto
    - from: Vera Liderson. Maine, 1946-1961; 30 items (Reel 1)
  - Tilda Tanner
    - from: Nikolai Lindvall. N.J., 1960-1961; 2 items (Reel 1)
  - Toivo Ketola
    - from: Frans Järvistö. Minn., 1958; 2 items (Reel 1)
  - Kunnallis-Sanomat newspaper
    - from: John Hartman. Mass., undated; 1 items (Reel 1)
  - Helli Välimäki
    - from: Alex Rinne. N.Y., 1949-1951; 5 items (Reel 1)
  - Anni Ylinen
    - from: Gustava Davidson. Ont., 1946-1952; 2 items (Reel 1)
  - Anni Rosendal
    - from: Aino Norkooli. Ont., 1923-1940; 10 items (Reel 1)
  - Erkki Ketonen
    - from: Mimmi Lahtinen. Ont., 1958-1961; 2 items (Reel 1)
    - from: Sakari Ketonen. Ont., 1961-1963; 3 items (Reel 1)
  - Mr. Aaltonen
    - from: Mauno Aaltonen. Soviet Union, 1925; 1 items (Reel 1)
  - Saara Vahanen
    - from: Fanni Ylitalo. Ont., 1961; 1 items (Reel 1)
  - Helmi Salo
    - from: Toivo Harjunpää. Calif., 1963; 1 items (Reel 1)
  - Hilda Vahonen
    - from: Niilo Vahonen. Ont., 1958-1963; 5 items (Reel 1)
  - Jenny Seppanen
    - from: Eeva Seppänen, Ont., 1958-1961; 12 items (Reel 1)
  - Maria Kulmanen
    - from: Sanni Virtanen. Verm., Ohio, 1948-1951; 5 items (Reel 1)
  - Eeva Takala
    - from: Warren Mory. Costa Rica, 1952; 1 items (Reel 1)
- Eurajoki, letters to
  - Yrjö Ketola
    - from: Joel Ketola. Ont., 1924; 2 items (Reel 1)
    - from: Maria Ketola. Mass., Pa., N.Y., 1910-1927; 17 items (Reel 1)
  - Martta Mattila
    - from Lydia Hill, Minn., 1956-1959; 9 items (Reel 1)
  - Anna Nuurma
    - from Lydia Hill. Minn., 1919-1969; 69 items (Reel 1)
  - Juho Santamaa
    - from: Iivari Jokinen, Wash., 1952; 2 items (Reel 1)
  - Aune Karppinen
    - from: Linda Tavastland, N.Y., 1964; 1 items (Reel 1)
  - Eevi Saherma
    - from: Laura Nordman, Cal., 1961; 1 items (Reel 1)
    - from: Helmi Surmont, Cal., 1963; 1 items (Reel 1)
  - :Sandra Varjo
    - from: Kalle Ranne, Minn., 1962; 1 items (Reel 1)
  - Elvi Friberg
    - from: Fanny Stenroos, Mass., 1964; 1 items (Reel 1)
  - Maria Haapala
    - from: Linda Tavastland, N.Y., 1964; 1 items (Reel 1)
    - from: Aino Satama, N.Y., 1960; 1 items (Reel 1)
    - from: Alice Benson, N.Y., 1963; 1 items (Reel 1)
    - from: Aarne Aaltonen, Australia, 1953; 1 items (Reel 1)
  - Jenny Hakamaa
    - from: Linda Tavastland. N.Y., 1960; 1 items (Reel 1)
    - from: Juho Valtonen. Conn., 1962; 1 items (Reel 1)
  - Vihtori Harju
    - from: Iisak Salo. Alaska, 1952; 1 items (Reel 1)
  - Olga Mikkola
    - from: Vihtori Mattila. N.Y., 1926-1936; 7 items (Reel 1)
    - from: Vihtori Koski. (Reel 1)
  - Vihtori Mikkola
    - from: Jalmari Mikkola. N.Y., 1930-1933; 4 items (Reel 1)
    - from: Jalmari Mikkola. N.Y., 1934-1959; 34 items (Reel 2)
    - from: Fanny Nikmo, N.Y., 1934; 3 items (Reel 2)
    - from: Aini Eronen. Ont., 1952-1959; 8 items (Reel 2)
  - Aina Järvi
    - from: Elsa Valtonen. N.Y., 1961-1963; 10 items (Reel 2)
    - from: Tekla Kangas. Quebec, 1960-1963; 5 items (Reel 2)
    - from: Maiju Haapala., 1953; 6 items (Reel 2)
  - Hilda Lindroos
    - from: Tekla Maki. N.Y., 1949; 1 items (Reel 2)
  - Hilda Lehtola
    - from: Martta Maki.
      - Crystal Falls, Mich., 1952-1969; 7 items (Reel 2)
      - Ill., 1961; 1 items (Reel 2)
      - Crystal Falls, Mich., 1961-1962; 4 items (Reel 2)
  - Jenny Vaatto
    - from: Ida Zakrajsek, Ohio, 1960-1961; 5 items (Reel 2)
  - Sisko Vaatto
    - from: Ida Zakrajsek. Ohio, 1959-1963; 8 items (Reel 2)
  - Katri Nieminen
    - from: Vilho Gronberg, Argentina, 1963; 2 items (Reel 2)
  - Hilma Ketola
    - from: Yrjo Ketola. Ont., 1929-1930; 2 items (Reel 2)
  - Iida Santamaa
    - from: Aini Warn. Conn., 1959; 2 items (Reel 2)
  - Taimi Ojala
    - from: Aarne Aaltonen, Australia, 1961-1963; 3 items (Reel 2)
  - Irma Järvi
    - from: Ronald Haapala., undated; 2 items (Reel 2)
- Hinnerjoki, letters to
  - Artturi Kuusisto
    - from: K. Laaksonen. Minn., 1903; 1 items (Reel 2)
    - from: Johan Kuusisto
      - Minn., 1902-1904; 17 items (Reel 2)
      - Newberry, Mich., 1906; 1 items (Reel 2)
      - Minn., 1907-1908; 5 items (Reel 2)
    - from: Isak Kuusisto.
      - Ohio, N.Y., 1905; 5 items (Reel 2)
      - Newberry, Mich., 1905-1907; 13 items (Reel 2)
      - Minn., Wash., 1907-1929; 7 items (Reel 2)
    - from: Gustaf Kuusisto
      - Eng, 1906; 1 items (Reel 2)
      - Newberry, Mich., 1906-1907; 2 items (Reel 2)
      - Minn., 1907-1959; 41 items (Reel 2)
    - from: H. Renfors. Minn., 1959; 1 items (Reel 2)
    - from: Oskar Laakso. Mass., 1910; 1 items (Reel 2)
  - Emilia Kreula
    - from: August Kulmala. Ohio, Wash., 1907-1911; 8 items (Reel 2)
    - from: Olga Koskinen, Ohio, 1903; 1 items (Reel 2)
    - from: Vilma Nummela, N.H., 1903-1910; 9 items (Reel 2)
    - from: August Jalo, Wash., 1908; 2 items (Reel 2)
    - from: Norma Eriksson, Minn., 1951-1953; 7 items (Reel 2)
  - Ilona Koivuniemi
    - from: Ida Nummela. Maine, 1956-1969; 20 items (Reel 2)
  - Onhi Koivuniemi
    - from: Saimi Airo, N.J., 1960; 5 items (Reel 2)
  - Armas Maantila
    - from: Hilma Lauri, Minn., 1948; 1 items (Reel 2)
    - from: Eleanor West. Calif., 1955; 1 items (Reel 2)
    - from: Elsie Williams, Cal., 1962; 1 items (Reel 2)
  - Anna Pietila
    - from: Kaarlo Pietilä. Wash., 1910-1914; 10 items (Reel 2)
  - Aura Salonen
    - from: Suorna Rainey. Minn., 1928-1963; 24 items (Reel 2)
    - from: Suoma Rainey, Minn., 1925-1963; 7 items (Reel 2)
  - Mandi Salonen
    - from: Impi Korpela, Mass., 1964; 1 items (Reel 2)
  - Unknown Recipient
    - from: Jalmar Haapanen. N.H., Alaska, 1915; 2 items (Reel 2)
  - Maria Mattila
    - photos (Reel 2)
    - from: Aili Ekman. Wash., B.C., 1939-1957; 2 items (Reel 2)
  - Paavo Selimo
    - from: unnamed. Maine, 1910-1912; 3 items (Reel 2)
    - from: August Tuomisto, Ohio, 1910; 1 items (Reel 2)
    - from: August Heuru, Ohio, 1910; 1 items (Reel 2)
    - from: unnamed. Mass., 1905; 1 items (Reel 2)
    - from: Oskar Harju. Ohio
      - undated, 3 items (Reel 2)
      - Baie de Wasai, Mich., 1938; 1 items (Reel 2)
  - Anneli Kotikivi
    - from: Maria Kilpela, Minn., 1963; 2 items (Reel 2)
  - Liisa Kauppi
    - from: Margaret Kangas, Ont., 1963; 1 items (Reel 2)
- Honkajoki, letters to
  - Aarne Erkkilä
    - from: Iida Laurunen. Wyo:, 1954; 1 items (Reel 2)
  - Auni Santahuhta
    - from: Hilda Holm. N.Y., 1962; 1 items (Reel 2)
  - Helle Ylituomi
    - from: Niilo Ylituomi. Chatham, Mich., 1924-1927 (Reel 2)
    - from: Tilda Ylituomi. Ont., 1947-1950; 3 items (Reel 2)
  - Helmi Santahuhta
    - from: Lyydi Nevala. Ont., 1963; 1 items (Reel 2)
  - Elna Heinikangas
    - from: Tyyne Muotio. Ont., 1964; 1 items (Reel 2)
- Honkilahti, letters to
  - Hilda Rekola
    - from: Juho Rinne. Calif., 1914-1916; 4 items (Reel 2)
  - Hilda Rekola
    - from: Anna Lahdemaki, N.Y., 1916; 2 items (Reel 2)
  - Frans Uusikartano
    - from: Frans Linden. Michigamme, Mich., 1903; 1 items (Reel 2)
  - Hilma Jokinen
    - from: Anni Kukkola. N.H., Fla., Ark., Wis., Ill., 1951-1963; 12 items (Reel 2)
  - Wilma Prykäri
    - from: Maire Bye. Minn., 1946-1961; 5 items (Reel 2)
  - Senni Salminen
    - from: Arvo Lindroos. N.H., Mass., Wis., N.Y., 1909-1929; 11 items (Reel 3)
  - Fanny Leihela
    - from: various. N.H., N.Y., 1909-1928; 13 items (Reel 3)
- Huittinen, letters to
  - Urho Palonen
    - from: various.
      - Wyandotte, Mich., 1946; 1 items (Reel 3)
      - Mass., 1946; 2 items (Reel 3)
      - Wyandotte, Mich., 1956; 1 items (Reel 3)
  - Aune Koskinen
    - from: various. Wis., N.Y., Minn., 1945-1963; 10 items (Reel 3)
    - from: Alina Lehtinen. N.Y., N.J., Soviet Union, Germany, 1908-1938; 120 items (Reel 3)
  - Väinö Mangeloja
    - from: various. N.Y., Wis., 1936-1950; 10 items (Reel 3)
  - Kyllikki Koivunen
    - from: Alina Hallam. N.Y., 1962-1963; 4 items (Reel 3)
  - Alli Mikola
    - from: Alma Erickson. Calif., 1946-1956; 12 items (Reel 3)
  - Loviisa Paaso
    - from: Ida Koivisto, Canada, 1963; 1 items (Reel 3)
  - Eila Värinen
    - from: Annikki Rannikko. Minn., 1962-1963; 3 items (Reel 3)
  - Anna Lammela
    - from: Samuel Lammela, Ont., 1962; 1 items (Reel 3)
- Hämeenkyrö, letters to
  - Eero Ihantola
    - from: Frans Ihantola. Canada, 1963; 4 items (Reel 3)
  - Bertta Virtanen
    - from: Lyyli Pettersson, Ont., 1956; 4 items (Reel 3)
  - Elli Haukipää
    - from: Hilda Ihantola. Ont., 1962-1964; 7 items (Reel 3)
- Ikaalinen, letters to
  - Lempi Puolaviita
    - from: Vihtori Hannu., 1946; 1 items (Reel 3)
    - from: from:H. Miller. Oregon., 1940-1950; 6 items (Reel 3)
    - from: Milja Moisio. Calif., 1961-1963; 3 items (Reel 3)
  - Väinö Vähätalo
    - from: August Makinen, Minn., 1960; 1 items (Reel 3)
    - from: Elvi Luoma, Calif., 1961-1962; 3 items (Reel 3)
    - from: Eli Kivisto. Cal., 1961-1963; 6 items (Reel 3)
    - from: J. Kivisto. Ont., 1960-1963; 2 items (Reel 3)
    - from: E. Moilanen. Ore., 1960; 1 items (Reel 3)
    - from: S. Niemi. Oregon., 1960-1963; 3 items (Reel 3)
    - from: H. Niskanen. Ont., 1961; 1 items (Reel 3)
    - from: S. Simola. B.C., 1962; 1 items (Reel 3)
    - from: John Luoma. Minn., 1959-1963; 3 items (Reel 3)
    - from: K. Lahti. Minn., undated; 1 items (Reel 3)
    - from: Kalle Lahti. Minn., 1961-1963; 5 items (Reel 3)
    - from: Mandi Walden. Wash., Que., 1960-1963; 11 items (Reel 3)
    - from: E. Anderson. Ore., 1960-1961; 2 items (Reel 3)
    - from: E. Lampi. Minn., 1960-1961; 4 items (Reel 3)
    - from: H. Hendrickson. Oregon., 1960-1961; 2 items (Reel 3)
    - from: John Lahti. Minn., 1960; 1 items (Reel 3)
    - from: E. Niemi. Ont., 1962; 1 items (Reel 3)
    - from: Lauri Alho. B.C.:, 1955-1964; 35 items (Reel 3)
    - from: Alma Johnson. B.C.:, 1961-1962; 3 items (Reel 3)
    - from: Eeva Koivisto. Ont., 1963; 1 items (Reel 3)
    - from: Ida Harju. Minn., 1960-1963; 5 items (Reel 3)
    - from: Aina Pedersen. Ont., 1961-1964; 8 items (Reel 3)
    - from: Kalle Pihlaja. Minn., 1961; 1 items (Reel 3)
    - from: Vaino Kuusi. Minn., 1961; 1 items (Reel 3)
    - from: Fanny Salo. Ont., 1960; 1 items (Reel 3)
    - from: Teemu Inkinen. B.C.:, 1959; 1 items (Reel 3)
    - from: Erkki Peterson. Ont., 1959; 2 items (Reel 3)
    - from: T. Tromposen. Alta., 1960; 1 items (Reel 3)
    - from: A. Shemeikka. Australia, 1959; 1 items (Reel 3)
    - from: A. Hakala. Minn., 1961-1963; 3 items (Reel 3)
    - from: S. Johnson. Ore., 1960-1963; 7 items (Reel 3)
    - from. Kinnari. Oregon., 1960-1964; 12 items (Reel 3)
    - from: Elna Metsa. Minn., 1960-1962; 4 items (Reel 3)
    - from: Joe Maki. Minn., 1961-1964; 4 items (Reel 3)
  - Emmi Huhdankorpi
    - from: Aune Kemppainen. Ill., 1938-1939; 2 items (Reel 3)
    - from: Fannie Lampi. Ill., 1939-1962; 6 items (Reel 3)
  - Emma Isoaho
    - from: Matti Saari. Minn., 1948-1958; 5 items (Reel 3)
    - from: Impi Hill. Wash., 1960-1962; 3 items (Reel 3)
    - from: Charles Torma. Minn., 1924; 4 items (Reel 3)
    - from: David Torma. Minn., Fla., 1946-1962; 8 items (Reel 3)
    - from: Leo Torma. Minn., undated; 1 items (Reel 3)
    - from: Wilho Hill. Sault Ste. Marie, Mich., 1946-1964; 7 items (Reel 3)
  - Hilma Koskela
    - from: Johan Koivisto. Ont., 1957; 2 items (Reel 3)
  - Lyyli Kulmala
    - from: Emilia Makala. Ill., 1953; 1 items (Reel 3)
  - Bertta Marjamäki
    - from: Amanda Johanson. Cal., 1956; 2 items (Reel 3)
    - from: Aleksi Marjamäki. Soviet Union, 1937; 2 items (Reel 3)
    - from: Robert Laine. Calif., 1945; 2 items (Reel 3)
    - from: Robert Laine. Calif., 1956-1969; 12 items (Reel 3)
    - from: Mari Valisalo. Mont., 1930; 3 items (Reel 3)
    - from: Hilda Niemi. Ohio, 1952-1963; 31 items (Reel 3)
  - Niilo Markkola
    - from: Eva Lahti. Chatham, Mich., 1946; 1 items (Reel 4)
  - Hulda Raiskio
    - from: O. Johansen. Alaska, 1962; 1 items (Reel 4)
  - Hulda Raiskio
    - from: Matilda Almusa. Sask., 1961-1964; 4 items (Reel 4)
  - Eino Peltonen
    - from: Ellen Luoma. Pa., Ohio, 1902-1915; 7 items (Reel 4)
  - Lea Talonen
    - from: Amanda Mattila. photos (Reel 4)
    - from: Lempi Maattanen. N.Y., 1952-1963; 6 items (Reel 4)
  - Hilma Vilppo
    - from: Fannie Mernto. Mass., 1951; 1 items (Reel 4)
  - Bertta Vähäniemi
    - from: Edward Watunen. Wis., 1947-1969; 8 items (Reel 4)
    - from: Aino Jokelin. Mass., 1951-1964; 50 items (Reel 4)
    - from: Hilja Koskela. Mass., 1952-1962; 20 items (Reel 4)
    - from: Martta Haavisto. Ont., 1948-1963; 13 items (Reel 4)
  - Anna-Liisa Hakala
    - from: Vihtori Hakala. Minn., 1946; 1 items (Reel 4)
  - Wilhelmiina Reunamäki
    - from: Johan Lepola. Seney, Mich., Marquette, Mich., 1902-1927; 4 items (Reel 4)
    - from: Emmi Niemi. Mass., 1913; 14 items (Reel 4)
    - from: Hilda Paananen. Mass., 1908-1930; 33 items (Reel 4)
  - Robert Ronimäki
    - from: unnamed
      - Sault Ste. Marie, Mich., 1904-1908; 3 items (Reel 4)
      - Minn., 1913-1922; 3 items (Reel 4)
      - Arnold, Mich., 1924; 1 items (Reel 4)
  - Martta Jaakkola
    - from: Helmi Jaakkola. Fla., N.Y., 1928-1941; 7 items (Reel 4)
    - from: Lyydia Karela. Detroit, Mich., 1950; 3 items (Reel 4)
    - from: Charles Karela. Detroit, Mich., 1954; 1 items (Reel 4)
    - from Lydia Jaakkola. photos (Reel 4)
    - from: Ida Jaakkola. photos (Reel 4)
    - from: Hilda Jaakkola. Ohio, 1960; 2 items (Reel 4)
  - Paavo Talonen
    - from: Hilma Carlson. Pa., Fla., 1945-1952; 39 items (Reel 4)
  - Antti Tervonen
    - from: Ida Walkama. Oregon., 1946-1964; 5 items (Reel 4)
  - Hilda Ojala
    - from: Alina Aalto. Minn., 1953-1961; 9 items (Reel 4)
    - from: Alexandra Lahti. Wash., 1934-1964; 20 items (Reel 4)
    - from: Elli Mantynen. Canada, 1954; 2 items (Reel 4)
  - Hilda Rannikko
    - from: Wilhelmiina Anttila. Ohio, 1964; 1 items (Reel 4)
  - Kerttu Hietaniemi
    - from: Edward Papunen. Minn., 1947-1957; 2 items (Reel 4)
  - Kalle Peltoniemi
    - from: Karl Mattila. Minn., 1946; 1 items (Reel 4)
    - from: Lempi Kirmo. Dukes, Mich., 1946; 2 items (Reel 4)
  - Juho Rantala
    - from: Vilho Laakso. Newberry, Mich., 1956-1964; 4 items (Reel 4)
  - Aune Yli-Paavola
    - from: Elin Lampi. Rock, Mich., 1936-1940; 4 items (Reel 4)
    - from: Tyyne Nummelin
      - Wis., 1937-1940; 6 items (Reel 4)
      - Rock, Mich., 1945-1950; 3 items (Reel 4)
      - Ohio, 1951; 1 items (Reel 4)
      - Rock, Mich., 1953; 2 items (Reel 4)
  - Aliina Esko
    - from: Aleksi Ruusi. Minn., Wis., 1950-1961; 8 items (Reel 4)
  - Fanny Grdnman
    - from: Elsi Tommila. N.H., 1945; 1 items (Reel 4)
  - Hulda Ylioja
    - from: Jacob Maki. Minn., 1949; 1 items (Reel 4)
  - Martta Asell
    - from: Oscar Maki. Mass., 1960-1963; 5 items (Reel 4)
  - Taimi Lehtiniemi
    - from: Ida Levanen. Fla., 1955; 1 items (Reel 4)
    - from: Alina Jackson. Ont., 1961-1962; 4 items (Reel 5)
    - from: Elma Sund. Ont., 1962; 1 items (Reel 5)
    - from: Toini Lehto. Ont., 1961-1962; 8 items (Reel 5)
    - from: Maija Sokk. Ont., 1962; 2 items (Reel 5)
    - from: Toini Lahteenmaki. Ont., 1960-1961; 2 items (Reel 5)
  - Lempi Salo
    - from: Kalle Niemi. Ont., 1958; 1 items (Reel 5)
  - Fiina Ylinen
    - from: Hilma. Joki. Minn., 1945-1948; 16 items (Reel 5)
    - from: Martin Kotiranta. Minn., 1926-1948; 16 items (Reel 5)
    - from: Jennie Kotiranta. Minn., 1946-1950; 9 items (Reel 5)
  - Aune Grönman
    - from: Anni Leino,. N.Y., 1919-1945; 3 items (Reel 5)
  - Elma Hakala
    - from: Emil Hakala. Amasa, Mich., 1953-1954; 2 items (Reel 5)
  - Hilja Koskinen
    - from: Eino Maki. N.Y., 1946-1969; 2 items (Reel 5)
  - Impi Rantala
    - from: Mary Erickson. Tex., 1946; 1 items (Reel 5)
  - Martta Ruusuvaara
    - from: John Talonen. Wis., 1931-1946; 2 items (Reel 5)
    - from: Tyyne Hannu. Minn., 1947; 1 items (Reel 5)
    - from: Karl Talonen. Minn., 1945; 1 items (Reel 5)
    - from: Varma Parr. N.Y., 1947; 1 items (Reel 5)
    - from: Toivo Talonen. Wis., 1952-1954; 3 items (Reel 5)
  - Siina Kivimäki
    - from: John Westerlund,. Drayton Plains, Mich., 1962; 1 items (Reel 5)
  - Marja Lähteenmäki
    - from: Edla Makela. Mass., 1963; 1 items (Reel 5)
  - Elma Laukkala
    - from: Aino Uosikkinen. N.Y., 1951-1963; 19 items (Reel 5)
    - from: Tilda Pakkanen. N.Y., Fla., 1951-1963; 18 items (Reel 5)
    - from: Tyyne P. Ill., 1946-1961; 5 items (Reel 5)
  - Arvo Mäkelä
    - from: Frans Joki. Minn., 1946; 2 items (Reel 5)
    - from: Charles Joki. Minn., 1933-1954; 10 items (Reel 5)
  - Vilho Nyppeli
    - from: Hilda Paananen. Mass., 1961; 2 items (Reel 5)
    - from: Emma Niemi. Mass., Fla., 1949-1962; 30 items (Reel 5)
  - Martti Raitaniemi
    - from: K. Raita. Ohio, 1941-1952; 8 items (Reel 5)
    - from: Toivo Raita. Ohio, 1946-1959; 6 items (Reel 5)
  - Saima Raitaniemi
    - from: Mary Raita. Ohio, 1946-1961; 6 items (Reel 5)
  - Paavo Raitaniemi
    - from: Kaarlo Raita. Fla., 1962-1964; 2 items (Reel 5)
    - from: Toivo Raita. Ohio, 1961; 2 items (Reel 5)
  - Tyyne Raitaniemi
    - from: Frank Levanpaa. Wis., 1960-1963; 2 items (Reel 5)
  - IIilja Stenberg
    - from: Hilja Ranta.
      - Ohio, 1924; 6 items (Reel 5)
      - Marquette, Mich., 1951; 1 items (Reel 5)
  - Hilma Tuuri
    - from: Ahti Tuuri. N.Y., Cal., 1950-1957; 13 items (Reel 5)
  - Olga Änkö
    - from: Elsi Tomilla. N.H., 1947-1948; 2 items (Reel 5)